A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Program Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of James H. Lapple FA661
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Program Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of James H. Lapple
1988-1997 (Bulk: 1990-1994)
1990-1994
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lapple, James H.
Ford Foundation
FA661
4.04 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 3 series by file type.
Scope and Contents
Program reviews and meetings, budgets, field office records and travel files.
- Program Reviews and Meetings, 1988-1994; I
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Schedules, 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Budgets -- Budget Discussion Agenda, 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Accounting Software Review, 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Field Office Grants System, 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Original Representatives Letter and Planning Memoranda, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Participants List, Dinner Attendees (folder 1), 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Participants List (folder 2), 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Meeting Costs, 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Ford Foundation Archives -- Meeting Agenda, Retention Guidelines, Risk Management for Field Offices Summary, Information on Preparing and Controlling Files, etc., 1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting -- Miscellaneous Meeting Materials, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - May Administrative Meeting - Agenda, Fiscal Report, FOGS Information, May 15-23, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Southeast Asia Regional Meeting -- Bangkok (June 11-12, 1992) (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Office of the Vice President and Grant Administration, May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Urban Poverty (cost center 120), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Rights and Social Justice (cost center 130), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Government and Public Policy (cost center 135), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- International Affairs Program (cost center 140), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Education and Culture (cost center 150), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Rural Poverty and Research (cost center 170), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Reproductive Health and Population (cost center 180), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Program Related Investments (cost center 610), May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Africa and the Middle East, May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Latin America, May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- Asia, May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 7 Month Budget Review -- List of Errors and Handwritten Budget List Notes, May 1993 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Regional Meeting -- Audit Session, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Program Review (Box 1)
  - 1993 USIAP Program Review -- Education and Culture Program Review, Feb 9, 1993 (Box 1)
  - 1993 USIAP Program Review -- International Affairs Program Review, Feb 10, 1993 (Box 1)
  - 1993 USIAP Program Review -- PRI, RPR, RHP, UP Program Reviews, Jan-Feb 1993 (Box 1)
  - USIAP Program Review Fiscal Year 1994 -- RSJ, GPP, RHP, Nov-Dec 1993 (Box 1)
  - USIAP Program Review Fiscal Year 1994 -- E&C, Dec 14, 1993 (Box 1)
  - USIAP Program Review Fiscal Year 1994 -- Media Projects Program Review, Feb 1, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Asia Regional Meeting (February 1994) -- Meeting Preparation Materials, Administrative Procedures and Manuals for Field Offices, Field Office Inventory Lists, etc., 1988-1994 (Box 1)
- Budgets, 1990-1994; II
  - Ford Foundation USIAP Budgets Fiscal Year 1991 (as of August 1990), Aug 1990 (Box 1)
  - USIAP Fiscal Year 1992 Budgets Final (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1992 Budgets (other) -- DCP Ratios, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1992 Budgets (other) -- Presidents Review for Fiscal Year 1991, incl. Staff Count Analysis (Box 1)
  - Fiscal Year 1992 Budgets (other) -- USIAP Ratios, 1991 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Budget Process, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Ratios, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Budget Year End Follow-up (folder 1), 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Budget Year End Accrual Follow-up (folder 2), 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Final 1992 Staff Count -- Maddaline Kostyra Memorandum, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Calendarization, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Audit Checklist, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Staff Count Analysis, Field Office Capital Projects Requests, Funding Availability, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Year 1993 Budget Summary -- Unit Reserve, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - April 1994 -- Expense Analysis, Actual vs. Budgets, Apr 1994 (Box 2)
- Field Office and Travel Files, 1988-1997; III
  - Capital Project -- Jakarta -- Proposed New Field Office Building, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Chile -- Open File, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Chile -- Pending File -- Personnel Policies, Lease Agreements (for office), etc., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Chile-Lima Transition -- Lima Severance Issues, Accounting Arrangements, Personnel Policy, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Delegations of Authority, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
  - Field Office Local Delegations of Authority -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports (incl. photograph), 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Field Office Grants System (FOGS) -- Cairo -- Installation, Use, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Field Office Grants System (FOGS) -- Brazil -- Installation, Use, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Field Office Grants System (FOGS) -- Bangladesh -- Dhaka Office -- Installation, Use, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Pending Travel -- Office of Management Services, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Santiago Visit, Mar 14-19, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Summary of Risk Management Program for Field Offices, May 1991 (Box 3)
  - Thailand Provident Fund, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks -- Field Office Visits, Meeting Notes (loose notebooks), 1990-1993 (Box 4)